Guide to the Winterhouse Art and Design Collection of Ezra Winter
Yale University Arts Library
Winterhouse Art and Design Collection of Ezra Winter
1901-2011
ART 17
Yale University Arts Library
14
(12 boxes)
The collection contains published as well as archival materials relating to the life and works of Ezra Winter (1886-1949). The collection reflects research undertaken by Jessica Helfand for the "Ezra Winter Project," a visual biography of Ezra Winter published online in 12 parts with Design Observer, the leading international graphic design blog of which Helfand is a founding editor.
Helfand, Jessica, 1960-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Jessica Helfand and William Drenttel, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Ezra Augustus Winter (1886-1949) was an American painter, illustrator, and muralist. He was born in Manistee, Michigan, and died in Falls Village, Litchfield County, Connecticut.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains published as well as archival materials relating to the life and works of Ezra Winter (1886-1949). The collection reflects research undertaken by Jessica Helfand for the "Ezra Winter Project," a visual biography of Ezra Winter published online in 12 parts with Design Observer, the leading international graphic design blog of which Helfand is a founding editor.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Books, 1901-2011. II. Periodicals, 1911-2011. III. Miscellaneous Research Materials, 1913-2010.
Winter, Ezra, 1886-1949
- Books, 1901-2011; Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged according to the inventory provided by the collector(s).
  - Books, 1901-2011
    - American Mural Painting, 1902; King, Pauline (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Mural Painting in America, 1913; Blashfield, Edwin Howland, 1848-1936 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Memoirs of the American Academy Rome, 1918; American Academy in Rome (Box 7, Folder 97)
      Scope and Contents
      Notes: Edward Lawson, Volume II.
    - Memoirs of the American Academy Rome, 1919; American Academy in Rome (Box 7, Folder 98)
      Notes: Edward Lawson and Ezra Winter, Volume III.
    - New York Cotton Exchange, 1871-1923, Bartlett, Edward (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Notes: p. 13.
    - The Pageant of America. Vol. 1. Adventures in the Wilderness by Wissler, Skinner & Wood, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Notes: Page 163 "The Golden Hind" from the Cunard Bldg.
    - The Pageant of America. Vol. 12. The American Spirit in Art by Mather, Morey, Henderson, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Notes: Page 113, para. on E.W. and 1 illustration.
    - The Pageant of America. Vol. 13. The American Spirit in Architecture by Talbot, Faulkner & Hamlin, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Notes: pages 190, 192, 195, 196, 305, 306 – buildings that contain EW work, 2 with photos.
    - The Tudor Wench by Thane, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Notes: Faceplate, painting by EW $25.
    - Murals by American Painters & Photographers, 1932; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - News Releases Relating to the Life & Times of George Washington by United States George Washington Bicentennial Commission, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Notes: p.68 E.W. on Fine Arts Commission.
    - George Rogers Clark Memorial, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 129)
      Notes: Paperback on Memorial & Vincennes
    - Art in Federal Buildings: An Illustrated Record of the Treasury Department's New Program in Painting & Sculpture, 1936; Bruce, Edward, 1879-1943; Watson, Forbes (Box 7, Folder 99)
      Notes: Page 22. One illustration-Ceiling Painting, Industrial Trust Savings Bank, Providence, Rhode Island.
    - The History of American Painting, 1936; Isham, Samuel, 1855-1914 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Notes: P.584 mentions E.W.
    - A Complete History of the United States, 1936; Wood, Clement, 1888-1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Notes: Plate XIII - Mural from George Rogers Clark Memorial
    - Listen for a Lonesome Drum: A York State Chronicle, 1936; Carmer, Carl Lamson, 1893-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Notes: P.52 mention
    - The Federal Reserve System, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Notes: P.14, image of mural by E.W.
    - Radio City Music Hall Pictorial, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 100)
    - Official Guide Book: The World's Fair of 1940 in New York (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Notes: P.129 list of murals includes one by Ezra Winter. We have an original book but the cover is missing.
    - World's Fair Guide, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Notes: Included with the 1940 guide.
    - ABC of Herb Cooking, 1941; Ellsworth, Mary Grosvenor (Box 10, Folder 139)
      Notes: Book written with Patricia Winter.
    - ABC of Herb Cooking, 1941; Ellsworth, Mary Grosvenor (Box 10, Folder 139)
      Duplicate.
    - "and hearing not—" Annals of an Adman, 1946; Calkins, Earnest Elmo, 1868-1964 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Notes: Mentions EW's murals in Cunard bldg. p.242
    - Rockefeller Center: A Photographic Narrative, 1947; Chamberlain, Samuel, 1895-1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Mural Painters in America, 1952; Park, Esther Ailleen (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Notes: P.178 listing for EW
    - Art in Modern Architecture, 1952; Bittermann, Eleanor (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Notes: P.33, Radio City Mural
    - Planter's Punch, 1962; Curtis, Margaret (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Notes: P. 189 mentions EW's parties at Grand Central Station Studio.
    - The Golden City, 1970; Reed, Henry Hope, 1915-2013 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Notes: p.44 Cunard ceiling, p.85 mentions EW
    - The New Deal Art Projects: An Anthology of Memoirs, 1972; O'Connor, Francis V. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Notes: p.87, E.W. mentioned as Artist from American Academy in Rome & painted in public buildings.
    - The American Academy in Rome, 1894-1969, 1973; Valentine, Lucia N.; Valentine, Alan Chester, 1901- (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Notes: P. 69, 208, 214
    - Barry Faulkner, 1973; Faulkner, Barry, 1881-1966 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      Notes: Autobiography of peer. P.110, 112 mentions E.W.
    - The National Register of Historic Places in New York State, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Notes: P.53 Rochester Saving Bank
    - The Rochester Savings Bank: 150 Years, 1831–1981 by Turri (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Notes: P. 58-59 photo of ceiling & mosaic by E.W.
    - The Center: A History and Guide to Rockefeller Center, 1982; Karp, Walter (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Notes: p.64 Ezra with palette, p.72 mention, p. 87 mural
    - Laugh With Hugh Troy, 1983; Troy, Conn (Box 2, Folder 28)
      Notes: p. 45, 55,57, 65, 68, 83-4
    - Thomas Hart Benton: The America Today Murals, 1985; Branchick, Thomas, 1951-; Braun, Emily, 1957- (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - The Illustrated History of the Supreme Court of the United States, 1986; Shnayerson, Robert (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Notes: Interior images of buildings.
    - A Historical and Architectural Retrospective of The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 128)
      Notes: p. 16
    - Great American Movie Theaters, 1987; Naylor, David, 1955- (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Notes: p. 62, 76 RC mural, p. 79 Eastman theatre
    - Painting America: Mural Art in the New Deal Era, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Jefferson and Nature: An Interpretation, 1988; Miller, Charles A. (Charles Allen), 1937- (Box 3, Folder 33)
      Notes: p.154 shows one of the Jefferson murals in the Adams Building, Library of Congress, Washington DC
    - AIA Guide to New York City, 1988; Willensky, Elliot; White, Norval, 1926-2009 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      Notes: p. 11
    - Diego Rivera's mural at the Rockefeller Center, 1990; deLarrea, Irene (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - Jefferson's Legacy. A Brief History of the Library of Congress, 1993; Cole, John Young, 1940- (Box 3, Folder 35)
      Notes: P. 86-87 Canterbury Pilgrims/Thomas Jefferson murals
    - Buildings of Michigan, 1993; Eckert, Kathryn Bishop (Box 3, Folder 36)
      Notes: P.68-69, Guardian Building. Mentions EW's work
    - Buildings of Michigan, 1993; Eckert, Kathryn Bishop (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Artists, Advertising & Borders of Art, 1995; Bogart, Michele Helene, 1952- (Box 3, Folder 38)
      Notes: p. 148
    - On These Walls. Inscriptions and Quotations in the Buildings of the Library of Congress, 1995; Cole, John Young, 1940- (Box 3, Folder 39)
      Notes: P. 79-83 Canterbury Pilgrims/Thomas Jefferson murals
    - Lorenz Hart: A Poet on Broadway, 1994; Nolan, Frederick (Box 3, Folder 40)
      Notes: P. 72 mentions E.W.'s parties at Grand Central Station studio.
    - The National Trust Guide to Art Deco in America, 1996; Gebhard, David (Box 3, Folder 41)
      Notes: P.125-126 Union Guardian Bldg.
    - George Eastman: A Biography, 1996; Brayer, Elizabeth (Box 3, Folder 42)
      Notes: pp. 252, 305, 454, 317-18
    - Confessions of a Depression Muralist, 1997; Long, Frank W. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Sidewalk Critic: Lewis Mumford's Writings on New York, 1998; Wojtowicz, Robert (Box 3, Folder 44)
      Notes: p.90-91, 94, 266 - comments on Radio City mural
    - Sidewalk Critic: Lewis Mumford's Writings on New York, 1998; Wojtowicz, Robert (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Carl W. Peters: American Scene Painter from Rochester to Rockport, 1999; Love, Richard H. (Box 4, Folder 46)
      Notes: E.W. p. 389, 392, 487, 586, 592, 647, 747
    - Diego Rivera: The Detroit Industry Murals, 1999; Downs, Linda Bank (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - Night Falls Fast: Understanding Suicide, 1999; Jamison, Kay R. (Box 4, Folder 47)
      Notes: p. 366
    - Wall Street – Financial Capital by Gambee, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      Notes: P. 59 color photo of E.W. work in Cunard Building
    - New York 1930, [1999]; Stern, Robert A. M., 1939-; Gilmartin, Gregory; Mellins, Thomas (Box 4, Folder 49)
      Notes: p. 528 B&W of Cunard Paintings, p. 655 B&W of Radio City mural
    - The Priestly Tribe, 1999; Perry, Barbara A. (Barbara Ann), 1956- (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Radio City Music Hall: A Legend is Reborn, 1999; Hannah, Gail Greet (Box 4, Folder 51)
      Notes: P14-B/W of mural. P44-45 Restoration of mural.
    - Water for Gotham, 2000; Koeppel, Gerard T., 1957- (Box 4, Folder 52)
      Notes: Image p. 95
    - The Conquest of Illinois, 2001; Quaife, Milo Milton, 1880-1959 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      Notes: EW mural on cover
    - Skyscraper Rivals, 2001; Abramson, Daniel M. (Daniel Michael), 1963- (Box 7, Folder 103)
      Notes: P. 130, Cunard Building photo/EW's work. p. 131 shows EW's murals in Bank of Manhattan
    - Cass Gilbert, Life & Work, 2001; Stern, Robert A. M., 1939- (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Alabama Architecture: Looking at Building and Place, 2001; Kennedy, M. Lewis; Bowsher, Alice Meriwether (Box 4, Folder 55)
      Notes: P. 10-11 One of EW's murals in Birmingham
    - Art Deco, 2001; Webber, Eva (Box 7, Folder 104)
      Notes: P. 84-85 Radio City Mural, P105 mentions EW
    - Art for the People, 2002; Becker, Heather (Box 4, Folder 56)
      Notes: p. 49, 67
    - Artists of the Litchfield Hills, 2003; Austin, Robert Michael (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Higher: A Historic Race to the Sky and the Making of a City, 2003; Bascomb, Neal (Box 5, Folder 58)
      Notes: p. 251 mentions EW's mural in Bank of Manhattan
    - Great Fortune: The Epic of Rockefeller Center, 2003; Okrent, Daniel, 1948- (Box 5, Folder 59)
      Notes: author criticizes Ezra's mural in RCMH. Pages 218, 223, 232, 244, 255, 345
    - Images of America: Rochester's Historic East Avenue District, 2003; Leavy, Michael (Box 5, Folder 60)
      Notes: p.58 interior of Eastman Theatre, p59 Ezra painting.
    - Frank Brangwyn: A Mission to Decorate Life, 2006; Horner, Libby (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Basics of Genealogy Reference, 2008; Simpson, Jack, 1970- (Box 5, Folder 62)
      Notes: p. 155-160 research of Vera B. Winter
    - Edwin Howland Blashfield: Master American Muralist, 2009; Weiner, Mina Rieur (Box 7, Folder 105)
      Notes: p. 130 mentions EW
    - Camoupedia, 2009; Behrens, Roy R., 1946- (Box 5, Folder 63)
      Notes: p. 138, 169, 384
    - Suicides by Firearm in Connecticut by Books LLC, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 64)
      Notes: p. 7-8
  - Annuals, 1916-1933
    - Architectural League NY, 1918 (Box 7, Folder 106)
      Notes: 1 illustration
    - Architectural League NY, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 107)
      Notes: 5 illustrations
    - The Architectural League of New York (Index of Exhibits), 1922 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Architectural League of NY 39th, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 108)
      Notes: 3 illustrations, cotton exchange NYC
    - Architectural League of NY, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 109)
      Notes: 2 illustrations
    - Architectural League NY, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 110)
      Notes: no illustrations, EW listed as V.P. & committee chair
    - Architectural League NY 44th, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 111)
      Notes: Saverin Café, NY Life Building
    - Architectural League NY 44th, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 112)
    - Architectural League NY, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 113)
      Notes: Bank of Manhattan Murals
    - Architectural League NY, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - Mural Society of US, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 125)
      Notes: EW listed as member
    - Society of Beaux-Arts Architects, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 66)
      Notes: EW listed as associate member
  - Catalogues, 1925-1976
    - The Chicago Academy of Fine Arts, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 131)
      Notes: p.6 Rome Prize painting
    - Exhibition of the Work of the National Society of Mural painters, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 67)
      Notes: EW's work is on cover
    - Exhibition of the Grand Central Art Galleries, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 115)
      Notes: EW listed as a painter, no illustration
    - Grand Central School of Art, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 125)
      Notes: EW listed as "school of design" faculty
    - Handbook of the Boston Public Library, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 133)
    - The Murals in the National Archives, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 133)
      Notes: brochure on Barry Faulkner's work
    - Adventures in Herb Vinegars, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 140)
      Notes: House of Herbs brochure
    - Murals in Main Banking Room of Bank, undated (Box 9, Folder 125)
      Notes: brochure with prints of EW murals for bank
    - The Thomas Jefferson Murals, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 128)
      Notes: brochure with prints of Jefferson murals
    - Works by Ezra Winter, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 68)
      Notes: Exhibition brochure from Berkshire Museum
    - Ernest Lawson, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 134)
      Notes: catalogue of 1967 retrospective
    - The Canterbury Pilgrims, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 128)
      Notes: Brochure of EW mural with photos
    - The Canterbury Pilgrims, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 128)
    - Ernest Lawson, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 134)
      Notes: catalogue of 1976 retrospective
    - Visit Historic Vincennes, undated (Box 9, Folder 129)
      Notes: Brochure with photo of clark mem.
    - SRDS: To serve the growing advertising industry, undated (Box 10, Folder 135)
      Notes: GW Bicentennial mural
- Periodicals, 1911-2011; Series II
  - Alabama Heritage, Spring 1993 (Box 9, Folder 129)
    Notes: Birmingham Library Murals
  - The American Architect, March 1929 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    Notes: NY Life Insurance Saverin Café. Murals
  - The American Magazine of Art, August 1921 (Box 9, Folder 125)
    Notes: Cunard Building, two photographs
  - American Mercury, December 1932 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Antiques, July 1999 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    Notes: Sargent Murals
  - The Architect, July 1930 (Box 8, Folder 116)
  - Architecture, April 1930 (Box 8, Folder 117)
    Notes: George Rogers Clark Memorial
  - Architecture, November 2002 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    Notes: Winterhouse Studio/House
  - Architecture, December 1935 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    Notes: Supreme Court Building
  - Architecture, March 2000 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    Notes: Renovation/Radio City/p. 60 full page photo of mural
  - Architectural Forum, July 1921 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    Notes: Cunard Building
  - Architectural Forum, April 1925 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    Notes: Strauss Building, a.k.a.: Continental Building
  - Architectural Forum, October 1932 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    Notes: Rockefeller Center, EW Mural
  - The Architectural Record, April 1925 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    Notes: Strauss Building (E.W.???) a.k.a.: Continental Building
  - Architectural Record, June 1928 (Box 6, Folder 79)
    Notes: Willard Straight Hall, photo of EW mural
  - Architectural Record, May 1932 (Box 6, Folder 80)
    Notes: Quest for Fountain of Youth/Radio City
  - Architectural Record, June 1933 (Box 6, Folder 81)
    Notes: Radio City Mural in ad
  - Asia, May 1924 (Box 6, Folder 82)
    Notes: Cover: study of Cabot's ship for Cunard
  - Asia, May 1924 (Box 6, Folder 83)
    Copy 2.
  - Asia, May 1924 (Box 6, Folder 84)
    Bound copy.
  - Christian Herald, October 11, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 118)
    Notes: Cover: The Harvesters by E.W.
  - Fine Arts Journal, October 1911 (Box 6, Folder 85)
    Notes: Prix de Rome
  - Hound & Horn, July-September 1932 (Box 6, Folder 86)
    Notes: Article on Mural mentions E.W.
  - The Indiana Historian, December 1997 (Box 9, Folder 129)
    Notes: Clark memorial murals, p. 7 and 11
  - Interiors, January 2001 (Box 6, Folder 87)
    Notes: Photo of RCMH mural
  - International Studio, August 1922 (Box 6, Folder 88)
    Notes: p. 443 Eastman Theatre
  - The Literary Digest, August 1922 (Box 8, Folder 119)
    Notes: p. 30-32, Eastman Theatre Murals
  - The Illustrated London News, December 1922 (Box 8, Folder 120)
    Notes: Eastman Theatre Murals
  - The London Studio, December 1938 (Box 6, Folder 89)
    Notes: 1938 bound, p. 319 EW listed as World Fair muralist
  - Michigan History, May-June 1988 (Box 9, Folder 129)
    Notes: Guardian Building
  - The Outlook, September 13, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 90)
    Notes: Photo of mural at Eastman Theatre
  - The Outlook, September 13, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - Preservation, March-April 2000 (Box 6, Folder 92)
    Notes: Radio City Restoration, Mural, p. 59
  - Reflections, Winter 2011 (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - The Register, Kentucky Historical Society, July 1973 (Box 6, Folder 94)
    Notes: George Rogers Clark Murals
  - Rochester Review, Winter 1996 (Box 9, Folder 131)
  - Saturday Evening Post, March 27, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 120)
    Notes: ???
  - Scribner's Magazine, May 1921 (Box 6, Folder 95)
    Notes: "The Future of Mural Painting in America"
  - Scribner's Magazine, May 1925 (Box 6, Folder 96)
    Notes: Mural painting. p. 559, photo of ceiling in Cunard
  - The Cunarder, May 1921 (Box 9, Folder 125)
    Notes: Vol. 1, No. 1, - E.W. painting in bldg.
  - Cornell Chronicle, December 2005 (Box 9, Folder 131)
    Notes: Panoramic view of murals by EW in Willard Hall
- Miscellaneous Research Materials, 1913-2010; Series III
  - Binders
    - New York City, undated (Box 9, Folder 125)
      Research Materials: Photocopied articles, letters and photos related to E.W.'s work in NYC. Included are about 10 vintage postcards and a few original photos
    - From Ezra Hunter not typed, undated (Box 9, Folder 126)
      Research Materials: Photocopies of Letters and Invoices
    - From Ezra Hunter typed, undated (Box 9, Folder 127)
    - E.W. Rhode Island/Washington D.C., undated (Box 9, Folder 128)
      Research Materials: Photocopied articles, letters and photos related to E.W.'s work in RI and DC
    - 3 Ezra Winter AL/CT/IL/IN/MI, undated (Box 9, Folder 129)
      Research Materials: Photocopied articles, letters and photos related to E.W.'s work in various states. Included are a few periodicals, 6 vintage postcards and 2 vintage photos
    - Misc. Correspondence, undated (Box 9, Folder 130)
      Research Materials: Photocopies of letters. 1 vintage postcard
    - New York/Ithaca/Rochester/World Fair, undated (Box 9, Folder 131)
      Research Materials: Photocopied articles, letters and photos related to E.W.'s work in NY State. Includes periodicals, 1 vintage postcard and 1 vintage matchbook cover
    - Family Friends and Peers, undated (Box 9, Folder 132)
      Research Materials: Photocopied articles, letters and photos
    - Ezra Winter, undated (Box 10, Folder 133)
      Research Materials: Photocopied articles, letters and photos. Includes two brochures and photos of gravestone
    - Muralists: Ezra's Peers, undated (Box 10, Folder 134)
      Research Materials: News clippings and photocopied materials on E.W.'s peers. Includes 2 catalogues and 1 vintage postcard
    - George Washington Mural, undated (Box 10, Folder 135)
      Research Materials: Photocopies and one Catalogue relating to GW mural
    - Misc Artwork, undated (Box 10, Folder 136)
      Research Materials: Photocopies and photos of various works by EW
    - Home and Studio, undated (Box 10, Folder 137)
      Vintage Postcards: Some works by EW, buildings where murals are, Falls Village. Photocopies of photos. Documents relating to Winterhouse.
    - Photocopies from books that mention Ezra Winter, undated (Box 10, Folder 138)
      Research Materials: Photocopies from books that mention EW
    - House of Herbs, undated (Box 10, Folder 139)
      Original Artifacts, Artwork, Photographs and Ephemera Related to Patricia's House of Herbs
    - Blank White Binder, undated (Box 10, Folder 140)
      Additional Original Materials on Patricia's House of Herbs. Slides of the Clark Murals. Letter/Materials about possible mural in Stanford, CT.
  - Misc. from Ezra Winter / Edward Lawson Banker Box
    - Finch, Pruyn & Co. folder, undated; Folder (Box 8, Folder 121)
      Photocopies of letters and invoices, many undated
    - Misc. Spreadsheets, undated; Folder (Box 11, Folder 141)
      Photocopies of spreadsheets relating to research
    - Architectural League NY, 1922-2000 undated; Folder (Box 11, Folder 142)
      Photocopies of all entries for EW in index of Architectural League Annuals. Documents relating to E.W.'s participation in the A.L.
    - American Academy in Rome, 1913-2002 undated; Folder (Box 11, Folder 143)
      Photocopies of documents relating to EW Rome Prize
    - "Ezra Winter" embossed, undated; Folder (Box 8, Folder 122)
      Vintage Folder of Winter Prints; orig. 1932 NY Herald Tribune clip of Radio City Mural, letter to Mrs. Winter., Canterbury Pilgrims prints.
    - "1867: And so they came", 2006; Bound folder (Box 11, Folder 144)
      Winter genealogy by a relative p. 47-60
    - Correspondence Washington DC, 1936-1939 undated; Loose papers (Box 11, Folder 145)
    - Photocopies of E.W.'s works, undated; Loose papers (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - Correspondence Relating to Rome Prize, 1915-1930 undated; Loose papers (Box 11, Folder 146)
    - Photocopies of EW correspondence, 1917-1929 undated; Loose papers (Box 11, Folder 147)
    - Assorted Misc. Photocopies relating to research, 1933-2002 undated; Loose papers (Box 11, Folder 148)
    - 2 House of Herbs Posters, undated; Posterboard (Box 12, Folder 162)
    - Supreme court ornament featuring EW design, 1998; Ornament (Box 11, Folder 149)
    - EZRA WINTER, undated; Large envelope (Box 12, Folder 163)
      Envelope containing additional House of Herbs original materials.
    - Edward Lawson, undated; Binder (Box 8, Folder 124)
      Photocopies of documents on Edward Lawson, including correspondence with the Winters.
    - "Ezra Winter JPEG", undated; CD case (Box 11, Folder 150)
      CD case with 2 CDs of Winter's works in .JPEG format.
  - "Edward Lawson" Shoebox
    These materials were housed together in a small paper box, and their original order has been maintained.
    - Landscape Architecture, 1996; Periodical (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Notes: p. 38 Picture of Lawson's Todd Gardens
    - Landscape Architecture, 1929; Periodical (Box 11, Folder 152)
      Notes: p. 171 article by Lawson
    - Shaping an American Land, 1995; Book (Box 11, Folder 153)
      Notes: p. 87 drawing by Lawson
    - Ferruccio Vitale: Landscape Architect, 2001; Book (Box 11, Folder 154)
      Notes: p. 34 mention of Lawson winning Rome Prize